BINATARI AKENE

Mobile: 08111036832 | Portfolio: https://binatari.github.io/portfolio2/ | Email:

binataria@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/binatari

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Computer Science Benson Idahosa University CGPA 4.38/5.0 2017 -2021

SKILLS

Languages

HTML CSS

JavaScript

Libraries

React

jQuery

Redux

Next.js

Frameworks

Angular.js Node.js

CAREER SUMMARY

Fullstack Developer with over three years of experience building and implementing solutions across multiple sectors ranging from fintech, entertainment, etc. Eager to apply my skills to build scalable and profitable platforms. Involved in the development of CMS systems at irecharge tech innovations resulting in a 40% increase in user feedback and retention.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Irecharge tech innovations

Feb 2022 - Present

- Initiated the use of CMS systems for non user facing systems speeding up development by 40%.
- maintained the accelerate web app for payment processing.
- Built, tested and distributed desktop applications
- Designed and implemented web applications along with 3rd-party software integrations as a web team liaison for all interdepartmental and customer-facing projects.
- Monitored team OKR's to ensure quarterly, monthly and yearly team goals are met.

Freelance Front-End Developer

Codelab LLC USA

May 2022 - Present

- Developed the front facing website for hagglex cryptocurrency crypto exchange service.
- Liased with product owners and product management on the realignment of the product/website to specifications

Freelance Front-End Developer

Compumetrics solutions

April 2022 - Present

- Involved in the styling and implementation of output and road documents from the vehicle management system
- Assisted in the development of the vehicle management system
- Integrated revalidation and renewal modules for the kwara state vehicle management system